Ayomide Ibosiola

Technical Recruiter | Software Developer

- enochibosiola@gmail.com 🤳 +2348099691225 🧥 100271 lkeja, Lagos
- ## https://ayomideibosiola.netlify.app https://calendly.com/ayomideibosiola in linkedin.com/in/ayomide-ibosiola

Data-driven Technical Recruiter capable of Advanced Boolean Search to identify and mine top candidates with a strong Software Development background; specialized in building web and mobile applications that are aesthetically pleasing and logic-driven.

There's nothing like the thrill of a candidate's enthusiastic "Yes!" to an offer, and an equally pleased Hiring Manager who just landed a top performer. Perhaps even more satisfying is successfully recruiting a superstar and then seeing him/her develop a billion-dollar product. Knowing my efforts impact the bottom line keeps me going every day.

In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements, currently building experience in Designing HR Processes, TechnicalRecruiting, Talent Sourcing, Strategy Development, Recruitment and Selection, Employee on-boarding, Payroll Management, HRIS, Employer branding, Learning and development, and other Human Resources functions spanning Tech Start-ups, Consulting, Financial technology space, and NGO sectors.

This has allowed me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver exceptional work to all of my clients.

Education

Apr 2015 - Apr 2019

BSc. Microbiology

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

Employment

Apr 2022 - Present

Community Leader

Jobs Meet Devs, Lagos, Nigeria

- Communicate mistakes software developers make every day in their job search pursuit with the heart of a Technical Recruiter and the mind of a Software Developer.
- Help developers avoid the regular pitfalls in hiring processes by using any
 collection of materials including animate and inanimate objects and human
 and non-human resources useful in teaching and learning situations to help
 achieve desired learning objectives.
- Share job opportunities for members of the community.
- Create systems for organizational growth.
- Building an all-round development atmosphere.

Apr 2022 - Present

Technical Recruiter (Freelance)

Remotebase, Lahore, Pakistan

- Sourcing potential candidates on platforms such as LinkedIn, and GitHub.
- Serving as an ambassador for Remotebase and representing her in potential candidates' first interactions with the organization.
- Performing pre-screening calls to analyze applicants' abilities.
- Interviewing candidates combining various methods (e.g. structured interviews, technical assessments, and behavioral questions).
- Coordinating with Technical team leaders to forecast department goals and hiring needs.
- Crafting and sending personalized recruiting emails with current job openings to passive candidates.
- Keeping up-to-date with new technological trends and products.
- Creating a seamless candidate experience through all stages.
- Actively engaging and promoting diversity and inclusion in hiring strategies.

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

Frontend Developer || Technical Recruiter

Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, India

- Pinpointed candidate motivators and used them to successfully recruit quality candidates.
- Analyzed job descriptions and communicated with the Hiring Manager (Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd) to clarify terms that could be vague; earned job satisfaction rates of 95 percent from candidate/company matches as a result of this attention to detail.
- Created new features, functionality, and capabilities, specifically in the Contract Management System using ReactJS, Ant Design, Material UI, and Java.
- Performed bug fixes and code reviews.
- Recommended solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the design team.

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

Technical Copywriter

Marketpath Inc, Indianapolis, USA

- Gathered and analyzed technical and product information from various sources to document new or changing product functionality.
- Developed product manuals, how-to guides, website help sections, journal articles, and other content that distills technical information with ease and clarity.

May 2021 - Jun 2021

Frontend Developer

Mezovest, Lagos, Nigeria

 Built an online payment gateway that allows businesses to make and receive payments across continents, currencies, preferred payment methods, and platforms.

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

Software Developer

Royal Crystal Airways, Lagos, Nigeria

- Built the Web Application for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip using ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Stylus, and ES6.
- Oversaw the outsourced Mobile Application development for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip.

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020

Frontend Developer

Midra Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria

- Maintained, optimized, troubleshot, and improved websites.
- Created standardized websites and mobile responsive applications using a mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Implemented applications and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Built reusable code for future use.

Jan 2017 - Jan 2019

Software Developer (Intern)

Lagosbuild, Lagos, Nigeria

- Standardized website output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.

Skills

ATS Software

MS Office suite (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)

Recruitment, Selection and Learning

Boolean search (LinkedIn and Google)

& Development

Leadership, People Management and Employee Onboarding

Vanilla JavaScript

ReactJS	VueJS
Ant Design	Material UI
Bootstrap	
Tech Recruitment Certified Professional - DevSkiller	

Certificates

Jan 2022

Jan 2022

Dec 2021

Apr 2021

Mar 2021

Mar 2021

Mar 2022

ReactJS for Beginners - Simplilearn

JavaScript for Beginners - Simplilearn

Getting Started with ReactJS Components - Simplilearn

Soft Skills Course - Jobberman Nigeria

Certificate of Language Ability - Emmersion

HTML/CSS and JavaScript - TestDome